<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog/post on breadchris</title>
    <link>https://breadchris.com/tags/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in blog/post on breadchris</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="https://breadchris.com/tags/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fashion starts as a Sketch</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/fashion-starts-as-a-sketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/fashion-starts-as-a-sketch/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t like how long it takes for me to figure out ideas. Too much code is written before I figure out what I wanted is not what I made. There is a bookstore near me that I frequent and on the shelf was the book Drawing Ideas. Through this book, I have come to appreciate the importance of sketching in unlocking creativity and exploring new avenues of value. Through observation and simplification, sketching allows us to see our ideas projected onto a medium, much like using our voice to sketch out thoughts verbally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I am moving on from Substack</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/why-i-am-moving-on-from-substack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/why-i-am-moving-on-from-substack/</guid>
      <description>I had a Substack where I would occasionally post some things on AI. The vision was to build a following, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t execute it. There may be some &amp;ldquo;blaming the equipment, not the player&amp;rdquo; here, but from what I have learned, my writing flow feels so much better now:
First of all, I think Substack is great. Its mission is clear, and overall, they do a great job executing it (much better than Medium, imo).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Sustainable Thinker Always Wins</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/a-sustainable-thinker-always-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/a-sustainable-thinker-always-wins/</guid>
      <description>You can think about a lot of different things all the time. Think about too many things and this becomes a serious problem, especially for those who have ADD. If you have a problem focusing on which idea to pursue, it is easy to experience the feeling of being lost. Life is happening, ideas come and go, but there is nothing for you to bring to show and tell.
I am not an expert in this field of study, but I do pay attention to what constitutes a “great thinker”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Can&#39;t Fold 1000 Cranes</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/ai-cant-fold-1000-cranes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/ai-cant-fold-1000-cranes/</guid>
      <description>youtube
Folding 1000 origami cranes sounds at lot easier than it is. When my engineer mind latched onto the idea of completing this task, I was intrigued by the foretold wish one would get in exchange for folding a bunch of the easiest origami models. Kids do this every year in Japan, how hard could it be? - On average, it would take me 5 minutes to fold a crane from start to finish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Got to Where I Am</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/how-i-got-to-where-i-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/how-i-got-to-where-i-am/</guid>
      <description>So i was in a really good high school https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poolesville_High_School and so there would be some ridiculously smart people who would work on things and because the program was so close knit, information would disseminate between the grades and so the younger group of kids would only get that much better. I got involved in cyber security because the older kids competed in a competition that was for hacking and they did very well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I hacked my high school, and you should too.</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/i-hacked-my-high-school-and-you-should-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/i-hacked-my-high-school-and-you-should-too/</guid>
      <description>- I have worked for Northrup Grumman and Uber as a security engineer and I built security tools that have been used around the world. The coolest thing that I have done in my life is that I got to help develop code that ran on every device that had Uber installed on it. The purpose of this code was to help the 20% Uber was losing to fraudulent trips. The talent needed to work on a project like this was so rare that I was hired on as the first team member, as an intern and later hired on as a college dropout.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I hacked your site.</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/i-hacked-your-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/i-hacked-your-site/</guid>
      <description>It isn&amp;rsquo;t your fault, you were just doing your job. Even if you wanted to try to stop it, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much you, as an individual, could do about it. Either I or someone else who vaguely understands how to code was going to hack you like this. Business requirements for shipping that feature out at lighting speed for your largest customer last quarter made this all too easy.
```js</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information About Gloving</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/information-about-gloving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/information-about-gloving/</guid>
      <description>- Since the EmazingLights site seems to be down. I have moved the information over here to keep it alive!
- ## Start Gloving
- Welcome to the Learn Gloving Center, the most extensive online resource out there for learning everything you need to know about gloving. Constantly being updated and contributed to by the world’s most knowledgeable glovers, this is your first and best resource for learning what you need to jump into the world of gloving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NYU Dropped the Ball</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/nyu-dropped-the-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/nyu-dropped-the-ball/</guid>
      <description>## How it went wrong
I have a pretty bad taste in my mouth with NYU after what they have done with CSAW over time. The fact that HSF became a CTF, quality went downhill, and then now non-existent is something that really bothers me. It had felt to me that there was a complete disregard for the exceptional talent pipeline that Nasir/Poly had established for continuing to build out cyber security at NYU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start with a Static Site</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/start-with-a-static-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/start-with-a-static-site/</guid>
      <description>Ok, there is just simply way too much shit that you have to learn to host a freaking website . Let’s make that easier.
Start with Markdown and hugo. Markdown is trivial to learn and making a website is instant. Hugo is a single binary you download, run and boom there is your website. A number of themes are available for you to check out and play with, but they aren’t necessary to start out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is for Nolan</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/this-is-for-nolan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/this-is-for-nolan/</guid>
      <description>## SOLID principles
The set of five design principles for object-oriented programming that were first introduced by Robert C. Martin. These principles are intended to make software designs more understandable, flexible, and maintainable.
In Go, the SOLID principles can be applied as follows:
### Single Responsibility Principle (SRP)
Example:
```go
type UserService struct {
userRepository UserRepository
}
func (us *UserService) CreateUser(user *User) error {
return us.userRepository.Create(user)
}
func (us *UserService) GetUserByID(id int) (*User, error) {</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We need LEGOs for Code</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/we-need-legos-for-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/we-need-legos-for-code/</guid>
      <description>## Playing with Legos
Legos are fun, they are composable. Code is not composable, not at least in the way we learn to code.
Different environments come with different constraints which end up with different code. Different ecosystems have different standards and ways to solve a problem.
Legos have been designed to have an incredibly rigid specification that has been upheld for many years. It is trivial to determine impostor bricks (I am looking at you Mega Blocks) from an actual Lego.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What holds us back</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/what-holds-us-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/what-holds-us-back/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know if I personally would say that my life has been “hard”. I hear people use this to describe their life; “I have fallen on hard times”. But I don’t know, it doesn’t seem to be a relatable feeling. I have had to solve “hard” problems. Whether it is a math problem with seemingly random symbols or trying to comprehend why my parents won’t get along with each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why soundbite should exist</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/why-soundbite-should-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/why-soundbite-should-exist/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR soundbite is a podcasting platform, supercharged by advancements in content discovery, to connect with your friends and your community before international influencers.
Authenticity is a commodity in modern day communication. When we wake up, we look at our phone, during breakfast, we look at our phone, at work when we are bored, we look at our phone, going to the bathroom? phone. Watching TV? phone. Avoiding going to bed? phone.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
