Hello, this is the second episode of High Thinkies.
My thoughts coming at you as they're coming at me.
So Alex and I were talking about cybersecurity-related things and what the hell were we thinking
about?
I forget what it was.
But I said, okay, so I had this idea.
So I just got finished watching this incredible video that I guess I'll leave in the text
below.
But this video was talking about the history of VRChat and I did not know just how deep
VRChat went.
It's absolutely incredible.
People have programmed so much and the marketplace is so large.
I wonder if high schools have VR club and our kids are learning how to program and post
a fun VR and play the game in such a elaborate detail, but this video is so worth watching.
It's incredible.
And it had me think of building a VR world for CTF players or other types of hackers.
I don't know what it would look like, but because interacting in a virtual world isn't really
easy for programming.
But I don't know, maybe there's something clever, maybe you can make a matrix universe
and give people excited about it, excited about hacking.
But yeah, anyway, it's high-thinkings for today.