I guess we're gonna try to record this thought with a regular mic so I guess you
could listen to this as kind of like a podcast all right I guess I guess this is
the official high-pinkies podcast because effectively what I can do if this
audio is embedded in my site is I can link this to hashtag high-pinkies and I could
put that out there so isn't hasn't logsec effectively made the perfect
podcasting platform because I could just record my thoughts and I could listen to
them back someone else could listen to them back maybe I have the the GitHub
like the script thing where I can turn speech into text but if I have that set
up then I can I can go back and turn turn my the audio that I'm saying until
like the perfect yeah the perfect podcasting platform I don't see why this
wouldn't work and actually you know what I can do is I could just record a
video so if I I wonder how well this would work if I just wanted to if I could
sync my phone with my remarkable then I could just take out a sheet of
paper right effectively that's what I'd be doing and writing down my notes and
that could effectively screencast right because you can set up a VNC
server on a remarkable you could screencast to your phone like I need to
figure out if you can do video or if it's feasible to do video recording over
VNC I guess you have to be connected the same local network which is fine I
mean you're probably on your home Wi-Fi network or if you're walking around I
think maybe you could do like a mobile hotspot
to connect to and then maybe you're remarkable I guess I need to figure out if you
have your iPhone connected or set up as a hotspot can your phone talk to can it
talk to I'm trying a blank yeah right okay right if you have a mobile hotspot
can your phone connect to another device that is shared on the mobile hotspot I
guess is what I'm saying so like as I'm talking right I can talk I can have my
words roughly translated into text right at least like the the words that are
if they're nonsense you can click on that word and it will take you to that point
in time in the audio and then I could also write if I wanted to just stream my
notes taking right because I have the remarkable I can take out my remarkable I
can have it be running a VNC server for that my phone connects to right because
they're on the same local network and they should be able to find each other and
then I just record that as a video and then I also insert that into lock set
because it can just reference notes so in the repo there would like for this
entry there would be the audio there would be the playback text which in lock
set mobile you wouldn't be able to see but you could write a plug-in right on the
desktop that
damn why am I doing a blank plug-in on the desktop that would
run as
JS that would hopefully this doesn't sound completely okay here and because this is
for sure this is like I guess that's the whole point of the high think he's
broadcast is that it's literally going to sound ridiculous and that's what
makes I think he's special you just record yourself thinking
yeah anyway I hope I'm able to listen to this back and I guess no I don't need
to listen to this back because I wanted to try to develop this because
theoretically I think he's with even with massive gaps the text that you read
would be different like you could just zoom around to the parts that interest you
so if I start talking about cooking right I could rattle off like an
ingredient recipe for example like like if I could speak naturally and I could
say to make a pie crust right and so or I just like say the words like new
recipe pie crust one part flour one part butter then a little bit of salt and if
I'm still here still just thinking so I would say change and
I would say change and then I would change the recipe step so for example I would
change the recipe step two what you would call it oh I would change the first
recipe step of pie crust to be combined flour salt sugar in bowl which would
then like mark that as the step and then for the second one right I would say on
this like podcast thing you like you tag it right so it's like I said the word I'm
just going to say we're in a word right Harvard I don't know why I'm taking
hard but I say Harvard and I pronounced it clearly enough that it added the tag
Harvard you could then create a whole page that is like the Grap Results of a whole
page in Logsack that is like the Grap Results of me saying Harvard right I search
through all these like text documents right because that's what this audio would turn
into right it would turn into a text document and it wouldn't be perfect but it's like good
enough right the conversion be good enough that I could go back through everything that
I've said right all my notes on something and recall them so for example let's just like
what's the stupid example of this like I say the word balloon right I say the word right
now and then maybe tomorrow right maybe tomorrow I go to a circus for whatever reason and
at the circus they have balloons right so this would be the second entry into my note
taking journal is balloons so now like through analysis of the text you can identify words
or you put that into essentially your personal search engine which I'm going to see right
so I have my notes up right now and I'm going to try to see if I can find this search engine
that I saved because I saw it before but I don't quite know so basically if this thing I can
definitely had it like somewhere search it was like index damn like so for example if so
there's this tool that I have in mind if it was like really fast it was like really fast
right so if I said like I'm reading hacker news right so I start my day and I just hit
record right and I start talking and it's like talking about hacker news then then I would have
this thought right of searching like I could then search for the tags like and maybe it works
maybe maybe I can do that so search for say hacker news and it was thinking about search now see if
when I saved that article as browsing the internet and I saved that article if it did text extraction
because right this is what I want to do this is the whole point of 50 is I can make it trivial like in
like a an API call a single API call I could turn a holy shit this could be huge like I could just
fork log sec right could I just fork log sec
I don't know is it like a hacker news and then search now index goddamn what was it maybe I can go
online it's very usually so I can leave my note now oh my god this is so funny my face didn't
cool type sensor that's a note now if I wanted to right I could tag it because it right it took
me so long to put this in right because that way I can search things from oh it's not called
hacker news it's called white combinator but I remember it in my head is hacker news right so and I'm
going to take this note right now and I'm going to say hashtag we'll say hashtag what's what I want to
say oh no I guess this is like I think he's going to link it to the page I think he is
whoops I come on I think he's that page cool
right so this thing and this is the right and if I had this this fucking the title of the page and I
wouldn't have to copy it all this shit down so annoying oh my goodness
it's not quite organized the way that I wanted to oh well be like close enough maybe
I think it's working hopefully
so I'm going on this train of thought I guess maybe I'll stop here see what happens