<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on breadchris</title>
    <link>https://breadchris.com/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on breadchris</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://breadchris.com/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>This is for Nolan</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/pages/this-is-for-nolan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/pages/this-is-for-nolan/</guid>
      <description>SOLID principles The set of five design principles for object-oriented programming that were first introduced by Robert C. Martin. These principles are intended to make software designs more understandable, flexible, and maintainable.
In Go, the SOLID principles can be applied as follows:
Single Responsibility Principle (SRP) Example:
type UserService struct { userRepository UserRepository } func (us *UserService) CreateUser(user *User) error { return us.userRepository.Create(user) } func (us *UserService) GetUserByID(id int) (*User, error) { return us.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What holds us back</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/pages/what-holds-us-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/pages/what-holds-us-back/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know if I personally would say that my life has been “hard”. I hear people use this to describe their life; “I have fallen on hard times”. But I don’t know, it doesn’t seem to be a relatable feeling. I have had to solve “hard” problems. Whether it is a math problem with seemingly random symbols or trying to comprehend why my parents won’t get along with each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why soundbite should exist</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/pages/why-soundbite-should-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/pages/why-soundbite-should-exist/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR soundbite is a podcasting platform, supercharged by advancements in content discovery, to connect with your friends and your community before international influencers.
Authenticity is a commodity in modern day communication. When we wake up, we look at our phone, during breakfast, we look at our phone, at work when we are bored, we look at our phone, going to the bathroom? phone. Watching TV? phone. Avoiding going to bed? phone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
