<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>thinkies on breadchris</title>
    <link>https://breadchris.com/tags/thinkies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in thinkies on breadchris</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://breadchris.com/tags/thinkies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why you aren&#39;t using gRPC</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/why-you-arent-using-grpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/why-you-arent-using-grpc/</guid>
      <description>From the first moment I saw it, I thought that gRPC was going to change how people transferred data on the Internet. What are we using? Untyped JSON to REST endpoint? Obviously asking for problems. JSON schema? Better, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to write that crap. Also tooling is annoying. GraphQL? Pretty nice. Better than gRPC when dealing with many related objects, but again tooling is eh. gRPC is built on Protobuf, a simple type system that has been battle-hardened by Google and other large companies over the past 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing Code Highlighting</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/testing-code-highlighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/testing-code-highlighting/</guid>
      <description>package main import &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; // Function to calculate factorial func factorial(n int) int { // Base case: factorial of 0 and 1 is 1 if n == 0 || n == 1 { return 1 } // Recursive case: calculate factorial using recursion return n * factorial(n-1) } func main() { // Example usage num := 5 result := factorial(num) fmt.Printf(&amp;#34;Factorial of %d is %d\n&amp;#34;, num, result) } oh look it works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive Redesign</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/massive-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/massive-redesign/</guid>
      <description>Well I have gone down the rabbit hole today on changing the way that everything looks. There are still some blemishes, but there is much more space for writing content. Oh, and I also added an AI feature where if you highlight the text then it will ask you if you want to use that as a prompt and the output will be streamed into the editor. I am super stoked with the progress that I have made here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The feeling to perform</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-feeling-to-perform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-feeling-to-perform/</guid>
      <description>I had some interviews today. In the first one, I was asked a question to which I knew the answer, but the words weren&amp;rsquo;t quite there. I felt myself looping on, thinking of the answer, and then being frustrated. Time passed, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put my thoughts into words. Somewhere deep in my knowledge I knew how to respond, but in the moment I couldn&amp;rsquo;t answer. Overall, the interviews went fine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I wrote some elm today!</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/i-wrote-some-elm-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/i-wrote-some-elm-today/</guid>
      <description>I had a friend take me on a journey through elm today while on stream today. The exercises they gave me were really well thought out and it was a lot of fun to feel how the code evolved between each task. Starting from a simple counter, it built up to where you were managing a list of list of counters. The cycle of building the thing that just works, and then refactoring it so it could take on more abstraction illustrated why elm&amp;rsquo;s architecture shines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I am coming for you transcription editor</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/i-am-coming-for-you-transcription-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/i-am-coming-for-you-transcription-editor/</guid>
      <description>A common theme in high thinkies is that I want to record my thoughts in a way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t get in my way of my thoughts. For example, writing down notes has been historically difficult and when the thinkies are coming in at blistering speed, it is difficult to keep up. So I started to just talk and record what I said. Audio files are super small. I also started streaming to also document what I was working on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What language am I looking for?</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/what-language-am-i-looking-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/what-language-am-i-looking-for/</guid>
      <description>If you ask anyone who knows me what my thoughts are on javascript, you will get a unanimous &amp;ldquo;he hates it&amp;rdquo;. Typescript helps, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix the problems. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe the problems I have with it are actually solvable without some radical changes in the ecosystem. Why do I care so much? Because I freaking want to build websites that stick around for a while goddamnit! Sites built with the &amp;ldquo;right decisions&amp;rdquo; today feel like they fall over from a strong breeze.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SF Feels like another Planet</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/sf-feels-like-another-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/sf-feels-like-another-planet/</guid>
      <description>I am visiting SF right now, and almost every billboard in the city has &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; on it. I need to build image upload so that I can show you what I am talking about. I get it, there is a lot of hype for companies to cash in on, so why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you?
AI (ML or machine learning for the pedantic) is super cool and can do a lot of things now.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
