<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>breadchris</title>
    <link>https://breadchris.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on breadchris</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://breadchris.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I want to use your code</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/i-want-to-use-your-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/i-want-to-use-your-code/</guid>
      <description>There is so much code that exists on the Internet now. Like seriously, an insane amount. And it only grows exponentially each day. Packages are written to combine efforts so that you don&amp;rsquo;t have to remember the 101 edge cases that come with checking if a number is odd in Javascript. When code starts to grow in number of times, maintaining a package that others depend on becomes more difficult. Does the new code break the old code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>building a plugin system for the web</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/building-a-plugin-system-for-the-web/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/building-a-plugin-system-for-the-web/</guid>
      <description>The Figma Plugin System Figma is a design tool that has become the industry standard, similar to how Photoshop became the defacto for photo editing. When everyone uses one tool, it only follows that there will be functionality that different groups of people need that isn&amp;rsquo;t immediately supported. To bridge the gap in functionality, a plugin system is the go-to solution for letting people extend a system how they see fit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A cool button goes viral</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/a-cool-button-goes-viral/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/a-cool-button-goes-viral/</guid>
      <description>Imagine a developer named Alex, who creates a simple yet intriguing app with a button that shows the user a picture of a cat when they click on it.
Alex chooses PostgreSQL for the backend, confident in its robustness and familiarity. At first, the app functions flawlessly, gaining a steady user base. Each button press generates a record in the database: timestamp, user ID, execution time, and the URL of the cat picture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>error checking is hard</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/error-checking-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/error-checking-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>Error checking is a complicated problem. It is like a garbage problem; everyone produces garbage, but no one wants to pick it up. Errors come from code that might behave unexpectedly due to forces outside of the developer&amp;rsquo;s control. Code accepts user input, and it will do its best to make sense of it, but there are scenarios where it is not possible for the code to handle the data that it was given (the code does addition but gets &amp;ldquo;hamburger&amp;rdquo;).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the modern business card</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-modern-business-card/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-modern-business-card/</guid>
      <description>I had this idea while I was at a rave (related to DID): I can define an RPC schema that anyone in the world can interface with. I can define different circles of trust for people who can hit certain endpoints (ex. “CalendarService.ScheduleMeeting” can only be invoked by my network on LinkedIn). I can also put different middleware on the endpoint (ex. Paywall middleware, rate limit, etc.). When a request comes in it goes into a queue, prioritized by some logic (ex.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>you have invented time travel</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/you-have-invented-time-travel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/you-have-invented-time-travel/</guid>
      <description>you have invented time travel. you hop in the phone book and go 5 years into the past to find yourself and tell them this: &amp;ldquo;First of all, yes time traveling is real, second, you should start reading these 5 things:
wayne
the following command “put it all on bitcoin and hold for at least 5 years”
books on mental health and relationship communications
like non-violent communication
all the engineering shit is fine and good but there are no rerolls on relationships</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My favorite button on the Internet</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/my-favorite-button-on-the-internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/my-favorite-button-on-the-internet/</guid>
      <description>A button is a deceptively hard web component to get right. A good button makes a lot of things simple to do. You only need to press one thing, and a lot of things happen.
&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;Design is not just what it looks like and feels like. Design is how it works.&amp;rdquo; ~ Steve Jobs
Beyond what the button does, it also captures intent. The user desires to interact with this button because they want what it offers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Go Proposal Process</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-go-proposal-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-go-proposal-process/</guid>
      <description>Underneath the syntax and runtime is a very important system that is often overlooked in a language. Usually, there is &amp;ldquo;the person&amp;rdquo; who built the language, and successful languages often come from the person wanting a language to suit their needs, not finding one, and then making their own. Over time, more people want to use the language, and balancing constraints of what is included or not included in a language becomes challenging.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>notes about coroutines?</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/notes-about-coroutines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/notes-about-coroutines/</guid>
      <description>Even though the &amp;ldquo;go&amp;rdquo; keyword is the same name as the language, you would think this is more commonly used. From my experience, go developers, including myself, will avoid using go routines and channels as much as possible. The reason is that it adds complexity that you often don&amp;rsquo;t need. Concurrent code unlocks a lot of performance as tasks that would otherwise &amp;ldquo;stop the world&amp;rdquo; only stop the go routine that they are on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>interviews suck</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/interviews-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/interviews-suck/</guid>
      <description>I feel like being put on a hospital bed and prodded every time I am in an interview. A rigid agenda of a strange conversation where the person on the other end is trying to profile you. It is an extraordinary interaction that I really hope improves over time. I usually get greeted by a nice interviewer, or someone trying to play nice at least, for the roles I am applying to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>8529 people have contributed to scikit-learn</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/8529-people-have-contributed-to-scikit-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/8529-people-have-contributed-to-scikit-learn/</guid>
      <description>The code that scikit-learn comprises has been committed to by 8529+ people.
python/cpython - 2640
numpy/numpy - 1581
scipy/scipy - 1447
joblib/threadpoolctl - 10
scikit-learn/scikit-learn - 2837
It is possible that some of these people introduced typo changes, or the code they contributed has been rewritten by someone else. But the repo was affected by them, no less. Their accounts were authenticated to contribute to the history of a notable library in the ML training community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Hacker’s Quest for the Ultimate Note-Taking System</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/a-hackers-quest-for-the-ultimate-note-taking-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/a-hackers-quest-for-the-ultimate-note-taking-system/</guid>
      <description>As the flickering lights of monitors illuminate the shadowed visage of a hacker, known in the cyber realms as Zero Cool, the mind behind the screen drifts away from the usual code and into the realm of daily organization. Amid the clutter of local Apple Notes, a thought emerges, tinged with the desire for something more open, more connected. “What if,” muses Zero Cool, “my notes could seamlessly sync with the very fabric of my digital life?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>to spa, or not to spa?</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/to-spa-or-not-to-spa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/to-spa-or-not-to-spa/</guid>
      <description>Website vs web app, what is the difference? How do you know how to make the tradeoffs in terms of complexity for a spa vs the simple HTML of templates? Managing state in the DOM is not easy, dynamic components require managing of more state. How does htmx relate?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>security affects everything</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/security-affects-everything/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/security-affects-everything/</guid>
      <description>As a security engineer, I found this talk interesting. It pushes for something that I agree with: the focus of ML security in research papers is primarily on novel adversarial attacks, but there are an incredible number of attacks on the supply chain aspect of training models that are often overlooked. The attacks from the papers are relevant but might require varying levels of attacker access to the system (ex., needing to observe model weights or inference confidence isn&amp;rsquo;t always immediately accessible to an attacker).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>structs in go</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/structs-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/structs-in-go/</guid>
      <description>In programming, where syntax and structure are the maestros orchestrating the flow of logic, Go&amp;rsquo;s struct declaration stands out as a masterpiece of minimalist design. But to appreciate its artistry, we must delve into the annals of programming history and uncover the symphony of influences that led to its creation.
Structs in Go, known for their straightforward and unadorned syntax, reflect the language&amp;rsquo;s overarching philosophy: to keep things simple and efficient.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>static vs dynamic types</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/static-vs-dynamic-types/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/static-vs-dynamic-types/</guid>
      <description>The debate between statically and dynamically typed languages has always been a hot topic in software development. Designing types for a problem can feel like solving a puzzle—fun for some and frustrating for others. But the real question is: Do you know how to represent the domain? While the alpha engineer may claim they do, understanding a domain comes from observing patterns over time.
The challenge in business, where code is most commonly used, is collecting and understanding the data needed to define these types accurately.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>failing miserably to scale kubes</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/failing-miserably-to-scale-kubes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/failing-miserably-to-scale-kubes/</guid>
      <description>I run a cyber security competition for high schoolers every year. Yesterday was the 7th iteration. Months of planning go into designing the story and putting together digital evidence for the competitors to try to solve a murder mystery. It was a special event because the organizers who built it for my high school self stoked my passion for security. Unfortunately, it did not go as planned this year. After giving the introduction talk to 350 students, the site got DOSed from the concurrent load of everyone accessing it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The case for a single binary</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-case-for-a-single-binary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-case-for-a-single-binary/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of software development, the dichotomy between local development environments and production settings presents a notable challenge. The ideal scenario is where both environments mirror each other as closely as possible, minimizing discrepancies that can lead to unexpected behaviors upon deployment. However, achieving this level of synchronization is fraught with complexities. Tools like Docker have emerged as potential solutions, offering the promise of containerization to encapsulate applications in self-contained units that can run consistently across various environments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>go dependency injection</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/go-dependency-injection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/go-dependency-injection/</guid>
      <description>Dependency injection has radically increased my programming rate. When everything is designed as a module, you find yourself constantly reusing things you have already written since it is the path of least resistance.
If you try to do this without the help of a framework, you will find yourself writing and rewriting the boilerplate code to connect dependencies together. Most DI frameworks resolve dependency graphs at runtime https://github.com/uber-go/fx
A dependency graph resolved at runtime is error prone and leads to confusing code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hack the planet | finding focus</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/hack-the-planet-finding-focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/hack-the-planet-finding-focus/</guid>
      <description>Hey y&amp;rsquo;all,
Maybe it is the poor Internet connection in Ireland, but I feel disconnected. Watching a site load brings me back to when you had to find offline tasks while waiting. Breaking up a hyperconnected workflow has helped immensely with building focus.
I am finishing up an annual cyber security competition I will run in Maryland soon. I&amp;rsquo;ll share when I am done; it is enjoyable to play 😊 After I clear that off my plate, my focus will fall on building a course on service design patterns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>reply to &#34;sensible web stack decisions&#34;</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/reply-to-sensible-web-stack-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/reply-to-sensible-web-stack-decisions/</guid>
      <description>In response to my previous post:
martinsos:
I like it, very practical and honest! No preaching, just direct opinions. Quite fresh for a web dev article. Btw I competely shared that view on Tailwind that you had at the start, and I still have it in part, just because I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough time to learn more of it. It still seems weird that we are putting all the style directly into html, I can&amp;rsquo;t read that and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t show the intention, but I think I read they are not against classes at the end, it is just that even them you woudl then define with Tailwind.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what happened to irc?</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/what-happened-to-irc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/what-happened-to-irc/</guid>
      <description>I get that it took a while for IRCv3 to come out, but the more I think about my ideal form of communication, the more it looks like IRC. I mostly communicate with Simple text comms, with the occasional voice/video chat. I also want to be able to write bots to receive and send messages on channels. Moderation controls are important for larger channels.
There is a Go server/client implementation, ergo, that I am excited to try out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>sensible web stack decisions</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/sensible-web-stack-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/sensible-web-stack-decisions/</guid>
      <description>I have so much goddamn respect for web developers. A long list of side projects has consumed a significant amount of my time and have been riddled with frustration. What is most frustrating when writing a web app is understanding what tools to use. React, Vue, Svelte? Tailwind, the component library of the week, SASS, CSS? Everyone has opinions, and the &amp;ldquo;principled&amp;rdquo; stances are mostly comparisons against other technologies. Over the past few years, I have spent a lot of time considering how to build web apps with a &amp;ldquo;modern&amp;rdquo; approach.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>anatomy of syntax</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/anatomy-of-syntax/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/anatomy-of-syntax/</guid>
      <description>Something I do not see often in programming language books is a concise explanation of semantic structures that are typically used. For example, in a Java method, there are different modifiers you can apply to the function to change how it behaves (public, private, static, etc.) Usually, the syntax is introduced and it is talked about at length, covering the many edge cases that might exist or the syntax is introduced in passing as an example requires a reader&amp;rsquo;s comprehension of the topic, referencing a later section for the explaination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>take notes to understand your language</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/take-notes-to-understand-your-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/take-notes-to-understand-your-language/</guid>
      <description>Someone probably looked up one day and said, &amp;ldquo;That is the &amp;lsquo;sky&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo; They told their friends, and then they told their friends. At some point, when anyone looked up at the vast expanse above them and needed a way to describe it, the word that came to mind was &amp;ldquo;sky.&amp;rdquo;
Maybe there is something that you are looking at in your life that will have a similar story one day. It might not be as profound as naming &amp;ldquo;sky,&amp;rdquo; but it describes a service we use like &amp;ldquo;Google&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Uber.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>a very B movie plot</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/a-very-b-movie-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/a-very-b-movie-plot/</guid>
      <description>Isabella is a very cute artist and James is a very handsome programmer. He likes spending time with her and she likes spending time with him. take inspiration from Eternal Sunshine of a Spotless Mind story and write me a screenplay script for this movie. Add a twist to the story, where there is some confusion and there is a strain on a relationship.
let me think&amp;hellip;
Title: Eternal Connection</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>finding a balance while coding</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/finding-a-balance-while-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/finding-a-balance-while-coding/</guid>
      <description>When coding, have you ever stopped to ask the question: why am I doing this? Maybe it is a fleeting thought before you return to squeezing out a few more milliseconds on your page load.
As creators of software and websites, we often get caught up in the never-ending pursuit of optimization. We constantly strive to make our code more efficient, our algorithms faster, and our page load times shorter. But in our relentless quest for optimization, we may lose sight of the bigger picture.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Free&#39;s top books</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/frees-top-books/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/frees-top-books/</guid>
      <description>Free is a YC founder who is very smart and handsome. Here are some of his favorite books:
Designing Data Driven Applications by Martin Kleppmann - amazon
Data is at the center of many challenges in system design today. Difficult issues need to be figured out, such as scalability, consistency, reliability, efficiency, and maintainability. In addition, we have an overwhelming variety of tools, including relational databases, NoSQL datastores, stream or batch processors, and message brokers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>go test</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/go-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/go-test/</guid>
      <description>Testing in software development often finds itself at the tail end of the feature development cycle, sometimes viewed as a necessary evil to uphold code coverage metrics rather than an integral part of the development process. However, the significance of testing cannot be overstated—the safety net ensures our towering stack of dependencies doesn&amp;rsquo;t collapse at the slightest touch.
A quick Google search on &amp;ldquo; testing&amp;rdquo; unveils a fascinating landscape of testing frameworks across various programming languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NSFW</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/nsfw/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/nsfw/</guid>
      <description>Their lovemaking was passionate, if quiet; she felt every atom of her body, his body, heavy in their node of space/time, replete with potential. Calvin breathed harshly beneath her, and she threw her hips into it with vigorous intensity, pressuring and sliding away from the place where their bodies were joined in abandon and rapidity. His eyes fluttered closed and he had to muffle a hoarse shout, and she felt him coming inside of her; when his thumb slid up to caress her clitoris, with a touch both gentle and firm, she came, too; and then again, as he returned the touch almost as soon as the first wave of convulsions had left her.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>things I need from this</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/things-i-need-from-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/things-i-need-from-this/</guid>
      <description>I need groups! I want to give people links to questions to have them respond to it.
site is easier to build make it easier for someone to start their own site. condense the work needed for building one down. I think it would be nice to have a file tree menu that would map directly to paths on the site.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>go run</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/go-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/go-run/</guid>
      <description>It may seem silly, but go run is my favorite part about go. Want to run your code? go run main.go. It is so stupidly simple that I could tell my mom about this command, and she would immediately understand. Like with most things in go, the real power in this command is in the effortless understanding of how to build and run everyone&amp;rsquo;s code.
But I can run node main.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>i need some hackers</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/i-need-some-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/i-need-some-hackers/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR - I need money for a non-profit international cybersecurity competition (open-source, too). Donations here, email chris@breadchris.com for sponsorship opportunities.
I am running an annual cyber security competition (mcpshsf, soon to be xctf) with my high school computer science teacher, celebrating its 8th? year, on March 14th. When run at NYU, it attracted incredible talent from around the US. Some of the alumni went on to form or join notable security companies/teams ( TrailofBits, Zellic, Google, Uber, etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the justshare podcast</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-justshare-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-justshare-podcast/</guid>
      <description>@KoaKilla figure out how to make this our baseline production value https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC3s0BtrBJpwNDaflRSoiieQ
34m oh god. not their new content
34m oh wow, you have to go back 6 years https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=tv6DyyvfPlw
33m Free Wortley Can you link a specific video Thanks
33m https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f8-7lhs4ky0
32m like i want to watch this content because it is well edited and cute lady talking about computers
32m we need to make an idea board of inspiration for the podcast</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join a Group to Save Your Life</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/join-a-group-to-save-your-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/join-a-group-to-save-your-life/</guid>
      <description>Joining and participating in one group cuts in half your odds of dying next year.
Every ten minutes of commuting reduces all forms of social capital by 10%
Watching commercial entertainment TV is the only leisure activity where doing more of it is associated with lower social capital.
Trends over the last 25 years Attending Club Meetings 58% drop
Family dinners 43% drop
Having friends over 35% drop
http://bowlingalone.com/?page_id=13
comments</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>you should try a partner dance</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/you-should-try-a-partner-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/you-should-try-a-partner-dance/</guid>
      <description>I have been going swing dancing at Century Ballroom every week since the start of the year. Swing is a partner dance that has leaders and followers. Before every song, it is customary for the leader, typically a guy, to ask a follower, usually a girl, to dance, and when the song ends, the leader finds another follower to dance with for the next song. For someone with social anxiety, this can be pretty intimidating.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Figuring out what to improve</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/figuring-out-what-to-improve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/figuring-out-what-to-improve/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, staring at something long enough is all it takes to figure out what to improve.
I moved from the TipTap editor to BlockNote, built on TipTap, but it comes with all the features I would expect in an editor setup. I especially like what they did with the concept of blocks, which has expanded my mind about what an editor can contain. On the desktop, the editor works pretty well; there is enough space to support the information the editor will include, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t look quite right on mobile.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>trying out the new editor</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/trying-out-the-new-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/trying-out-the-new-editor/</guid>
      <description>this is a test
asdf asdf
asdf
asdf
asdf </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why is fiction important</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/why-is-fiction-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/why-is-fiction-important/</guid>
      <description>So, I have been told that I need to read Foundation by Isaac Asimov, and there is a reason for this. What is that reason? It depends on the importance of knowledge and information to the survival of society, and it&amp;rsquo;s very pertinent today, even though it was written before the Internet was invented.
When was the editor so? I think it doesn&amp;rsquo;t show up; I need to re-implement it, but I could do/ask if it&amp;rsquo;s there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>hacker character with dialog in gpt</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/hacker-character-with-dialog-in-gpt/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/hacker-character-with-dialog-in-gpt/</guid>
      <description>Help me brainstorm a character
Character Crafter
Absolutely, I&amp;rsquo;d love to help you brainstorm a character! Let&amp;rsquo;s start by considering a few key elements:
Archetype: Do you have a specific archetype in mind, such as The Hero, The Rebel, The Sage, or maybe The Innocent? Each archetype brings its own set of traits and narrative possibilities.
Role in Story: Is this character your protagonist, antagonist, a sidekick, or perhaps a mentor figure?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>where did PNW companies come from?</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/where-did-pnw-companies-come-from/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/where-did-pnw-companies-come-from/</guid>
      <description>What are a list of reasons why companies like Boeing, Starbucks, Costco, and Amazon all came from the same area in the PNW?
There are several factors that have contributed to companies like Boeing, Starbucks, Costco, and Amazon all originating from the same region in the Pacific Northwest (PNW). Some of the reasons include:
1. Skilled labor pool: The PNW has a strong history of highly skilled workers in fields such as manufacturing, technology, and logistics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>deployment dashboard in the app</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/deployment-dashboard-in-the-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/deployment-dashboard-in-the-app/</guid>
      <description>i have a deployment dashboard for the app, in the app. it deploys to kubes. enter a docker image and it is deployed to the domain. you can update the deployment from your dev computer</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keywords for Top 10 Languages</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/keywords-for-top-10-languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/keywords-for-top-10-languages/</guid>
      <description>note: this does not include symbolic operators (*, ||, &amp;amp;&amp;amp;, etc.)
Python: 35
False, None, True, and, as, assert, async, await, break, class, continue, def, del, elif, else, except, finally, for, from, global, if, import, in, is, lambda, nonlocal, not, or, pass, raise, return, try, while, with, yield Java: 52
abstract, assert, boolean, break, byte, case, catch, char, class, const, continue, default, do, double, else, enum, extends, final, finally, float, for, goto, if, implements, import, instanceof, int, interface, long, native, new, package, private, protected, public, return, short, static, strictfp, super, switch, synchronized, this, throw, throws, transient, try, void, volatile, while JavaScript: 50</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LAN Party 02/16/2024</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/lan-party-02-16-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/lan-party-02-16-2024/</guid>
      <description>Write me a chickpea recipe that calls upon inspiration from Salt, Fat, Acid, and Heat. When writing the recipe, include details about what certain ingredients do as well as what the functional purpose of the steps are.
Recipe: Roasted Garlic and Lemon Chickpea Salad Ingredients:
2 cans (15 oz each) chickpeas, rinsed and drained
2 tablespoons extra virgin olive oil
6 cloves garlic, thinly sliced
Zest of 1 lemon
Juice of 1 lemon</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Naming is Important</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/naming-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/naming-is-important/</guid>
      <description>Why should we care so much about naming as developers? Code comes and goes, but language prevails. When a team is working on a project, they must develop a shared language on how things work, how they are structured, and how they are related. A database schema or language specification is such an important document that many developers will battle passionately over what columns are called. Mental models of how things go together are at odds when there are multiple words to describe the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Naming is Important</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/naming-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/naming-is-important/</guid>
      <description>Why should we care so much about naming as developers? Code comes and goes, but language prevails. When a team is working on a project, they must develop a shared language on how things work, how they are structured, and how they are related. A database schema or language specification is such an important document that many developers will battle passionately over what columns are called. Mental models of how things go together are at odds when there are multiple words to describe the same thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build dope shit with go</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/build-dope-shit-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/build-dope-shit-with-go/</guid>
      <description>The goal for this year is to: &amp;ldquo;write and publish something every day.&amp;rdquo; So far I have been doing a good job keeping up with this. In my pursuit to build larger compositions of thoughts, next year will be themed accordingly; I want to write a book. How does one go about choosing the topic to write a book about? It is probably something that you spend a lot of time thinking about.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>zoning out during standup</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/zoning-out-during-standup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/zoning-out-during-standup/</guid>
      <description>Every morning, as the first light bled into the room, the software engineer&amp;rsquo;s alarm would chirp, marking another day&amp;rsquo;s beginning. The routine was as predictable as the sunrise. Wake, stretch, sip a coffee, and sit before the computer.
The screen springs to life, revealing a grid of familiar faces. Standup meeting — the daily ritual. Each square held an expression; some were tired, some eager, but all were familiar. Pixels and bandwidth conveying nuances, the raise of an eyebrow, the half-hidden yawn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fabled Fusion</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/fabled-fusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/fabled-fusion/</guid>
      <description>We have created a fusion AI-powered trading card game where you can talk into a microphone, and it will transcribe what you say. Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss the features of this game. When you look at the camera, you will see stacks of uniquely generated cards. Each card is created by an AI based on a short prompt. We have various themes for these cards, and each theme has a corresponding image and a Chat GPT Element name.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fashion starts as a Sketch</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/fashion-starts-as-a-sketch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/fashion-starts-as-a-sketch/</guid>
      <description>I don&amp;rsquo;t like how long it takes for me to figure out ideas. Too much code is written before I figure out what I wanted is not what I made. There is a bookstore near me that I frequent and on the shelf was the book Drawing Ideas. Through this book, I have come to appreciate the importance of sketching in unlocking creativity and exploring new avenues of value. Through observation and simplification, sketching allows us to see our ideas projected onto a medium, much like using our voice to sketch out thoughts verbally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>some thoughts</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/some-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/some-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>You can also just talk and what&amp;rsquo;s being said just shows up in here so you&amp;rsquo;re just talking about stuff so I can be talking to you and we&amp;rsquo;re talking about like your hopes and dreams or maybe your past whatever it&amp;rsquo;s gonna show up in here and then
That&amp;rsquo;s a pretty cool idea! It&amp;rsquo;s like having a conversation that gets transcribed into a blog post in real-time. So, let&amp;rsquo;s talk about hopes and dreams.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why you aren&#39;t using gRPC</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/why-you-arent-using-grpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/why-you-arent-using-grpc/</guid>
      <description>From the first moment I saw it, I thought that gRPC was going to change how people transferred data on the Internet. What are we using? Untyped JSON to REST endpoint? Obviously asking for problems. JSON schema? Better, but I don&amp;rsquo;t want to write that crap. Also tooling is annoying. GraphQL? Pretty nice. Better than gRPC when dealing with many related objects, but again tooling is eh. gRPC is built on Protobuf, a simple type system that has been battle-hardened by Google and other large companies over the past 20 years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Testing Code Highlighting</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/testing-code-highlighting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/testing-code-highlighting/</guid>
      <description>package main import &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; // Function to calculate factorial func factorial(n int) int { // Base case: factorial of 0 and 1 is 1 if n == 0 || n == 1 { return 1 } // Recursive case: calculate factorial using recursion return n * factorial(n-1) } func main() { // Example usage num := 5 result := factorial(num) fmt.Printf(&amp;#34;Factorial of %d is %d\n&amp;#34;, num, result) } oh look it works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why I am moving on from Substack</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/why-i-am-moving-on-from-substack/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/why-i-am-moving-on-from-substack/</guid>
      <description>I had a Substack where I would occasionally post some things on AI. The vision was to build a following, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t execute it. There may be some &amp;ldquo;blaming the equipment, not the player&amp;rdquo; here, but from what I have learned, my writing flow feels so much better now:
First of all, I think Substack is great. Its mission is clear, and overall, they do a great job executing it (much better than Medium, imo).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Massive Redesign</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/massive-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/massive-redesign/</guid>
      <description>Well I have gone down the rabbit hole today on changing the way that everything looks. There are still some blemishes, but there is much more space for writing content. Oh, and I also added an AI feature where if you highlight the text then it will ask you if you want to use that as a prompt and the output will be streamed into the editor. I am super stoked with the progress that I have made here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The feeling to perform</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-feeling-to-perform/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/the-feeling-to-perform/</guid>
      <description>I had some interviews today. In the first one, I was asked a question to which I knew the answer, but the words weren&amp;rsquo;t quite there. I felt myself looping on, thinking of the answer, and then being frustrated. Time passed, and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t put my thoughts into words. Somewhere deep in my knowledge I knew how to respond, but in the moment I couldn&amp;rsquo;t answer. Overall, the interviews went fine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I wrote some elm today!</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/i-wrote-some-elm-today/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/i-wrote-some-elm-today/</guid>
      <description>I had a friend take me on a journey through elm today while on stream today. The exercises they gave me were really well thought out and it was a lot of fun to feel how the code evolved between each task. Starting from a simple counter, it built up to where you were managing a list of list of counters. The cycle of building the thing that just works, and then refactoring it so it could take on more abstraction illustrated why elm&amp;rsquo;s architecture shines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I am coming for you transcription editor</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/i-am-coming-for-you-transcription-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/i-am-coming-for-you-transcription-editor/</guid>
      <description>A common theme in high thinkies is that I want to record my thoughts in a way that doesn&amp;rsquo;t get in my way of my thoughts. For example, writing down notes has been historically difficult and when the thinkies are coming in at blistering speed, it is difficult to keep up. So I started to just talk and record what I said. Audio files are super small. I also started streaming to also document what I was working on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What language am I looking for?</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/what-language-am-i-looking-for/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/what-language-am-i-looking-for/</guid>
      <description>If you ask anyone who knows me what my thoughts are on javascript, you will get a unanimous &amp;ldquo;he hates it&amp;rdquo;. Typescript helps, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t fix the problems. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe the problems I have with it are actually solvable without some radical changes in the ecosystem. Why do I care so much? Because I freaking want to build websites that stick around for a while goddamnit! Sites built with the &amp;ldquo;right decisions&amp;rdquo; today feel like they fall over from a strong breeze.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SF Feels like another Planet</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/sf-feels-like-another-planet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/sf-feels-like-another-planet/</guid>
      <description>I am visiting SF right now, and almost every billboard in the city has &amp;ldquo;AI&amp;rdquo; on it. I need to build image upload so that I can show you what I am talking about. I get it, there is a lot of hype for companies to cash in on, so why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t you?
AI (ML or machine learning for the pedantic) is super cool and can do a lot of things now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Offline-First Editing</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/offline-first-editing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/offline-first-editing/</guid>
      <description>I like to check in, every so often, on the state of offline-first solutions. Most of what exists is focused around sqlite. Here are some of the projects that pop up frequently when I search:
cr-sqlite
mycelite
sqlite-sync
litesync (not open source)
sqlsync
The appeal of an offline-first experience is pretty well summed up by cr-sqlite&amp;rsquo;s tag line: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s like Git, for your data.&amp;rdquo; We are constantly generating data, and in many different ways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>im showing free</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/im-showing-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/im-showing-free/</guid>
      <description>Don&amp;rsquo;t think, write.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Figuring it out</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/figuring-it-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/figuring-it-out/</guid>
      <description>Someone shared this with me today. They said: &amp;ldquo;yeah when I read this I thought of your exact thing lol&amp;rdquo;. So it turns out that I am on to something. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a look at how well I am meeting Andrej&amp;rsquo;s ideal blogging platform:
Writing
✅ in markdown
✅ with full WYSIWYG, not just split view (think: Typora)
I am using https://tiptap.dev/ super easy to copy paste and add images</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Sustainable Thinker Always Wins</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/a-sustainable-thinker-always-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/a-sustainable-thinker-always-wins/</guid>
      <description>You can think about a lot of different things all the time. Think about too many things and this becomes a serious problem, especially for those who have ADD. If you have a problem focusing on which idea to pursue, it is easy to experience the feeling of being lost. Life is happening, ideas come and go, but there is nothing for you to bring to show and tell.
I am not an expert in this field of study, but I do pay attention to what constitutes a “great thinker”.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Can&#39;t Fold 1000 Cranes</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/ai-cant-fold-1000-cranes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/ai-cant-fold-1000-cranes/</guid>
      <description>youtube
Folding 1000 origami cranes sounds at lot easier than it is. When my engineer mind latched onto the idea of completing this task, I was intrigued by the foretold wish one would get in exchange for folding a bunch of the easiest origami models. Kids do this every year in Japan, how hard could it be? - On average, it would take me 5 minutes to fold a crane from start to finish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I Got to Where I Am</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/how-i-got-to-where-i-am/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/how-i-got-to-where-i-am/</guid>
      <description>So i was in a really good high school https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poolesville_High_School and so there would be some ridiculously smart people who would work on things and because the program was so close knit, information would disseminate between the grades and so the younger group of kids would only get that much better. I got involved in cyber security because the older kids competed in a competition that was for hacking and they did very well.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I hacked my high school, and you should too.</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/i-hacked-my-high-school-and-you-should-too/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/i-hacked-my-high-school-and-you-should-too/</guid>
      <description>- I have worked for Northrup Grumman and Uber as a security engineer and I built security tools that have been used around the world. The coolest thing that I have done in my life is that I got to help develop code that ran on every device that had Uber installed on it. The purpose of this code was to help the 20% Uber was losing to fraudulent trips. The talent needed to work on a project like this was so rare that I was hired on as the first team member, as an intern and later hired on as a college dropout.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I hacked your site.</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/i-hacked-your-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/i-hacked-your-site/</guid>
      <description>It isn&amp;rsquo;t your fault, you were just doing your job. Even if you wanted to try to stop it, there isn&amp;rsquo;t much you, as an individual, could do about it. Either I or someone else who vaguely understands how to code was going to hack you like this. Business requirements for shipping that feature out at lighting speed for your largest customer last quarter made this all too easy.
```js</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ideas at the speed of Github Actions</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/ideas-at-the-speed-of-github-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/ideas-at-the-speed-of-github-actions/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s see how fast this idea can go from my computer to my site. We are blocked on github actions, but still looking for a faster way to deploy and one that doesn&amp;rsquo;t require a github account.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Information About Gloving</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/information-about-gloving/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/information-about-gloving/</guid>
      <description>- Since the EmazingLights site seems to be down. I have moved the information over here to keep it alive!
- ## Start Gloving
- Welcome to the Learn Gloving Center, the most extensive online resource out there for learning everything you need to know about gloving. Constantly being updated and contributed to by the world’s most knowledgeable glovers, this is your first and best resource for learning what you need to jump into the world of gloving.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NYU Dropped the Ball</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/nyu-dropped-the-ball/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/nyu-dropped-the-ball/</guid>
      <description>## How it went wrong
I have a pretty bad taste in my mouth with NYU after what they have done with CSAW over time. The fact that HSF became a CTF, quality went downhill, and then now non-existent is something that really bothers me. It had felt to me that there was a complete disregard for the exceptional talent pipeline that Nasir/Poly had established for continuing to build out cyber security at NYU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start with a Static Site</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/start-with-a-static-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/start-with-a-static-site/</guid>
      <description>Ok, there is just simply way too much shit that you have to learn to host a freaking website . Let’s make that easier.
Start with Markdown and hugo. Markdown is trivial to learn and making a website is instant. Hugo is a single binary you download, run and boom there is your website. A number of themes are available for you to check out and play with, but they aren’t necessary to start out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There are different types of thoughts</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/there-are-different-types-of-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/there-are-different-types-of-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>small ones like tweets
bigger ones like facebook posts
formalized ideas in blog posts
ones that need to hold up to scrutiny like an essay
long cohesive ideas that are meant to take you on an all encompassing journey, like a book</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This is for Nolan</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/this-is-for-nolan/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/this-is-for-nolan/</guid>
      <description>## SOLID principles
The set of five design principles for object-oriented programming that were first introduced by Robert C. Martin. These principles are intended to make software designs more understandable, flexible, and maintainable.
In Go, the SOLID principles can be applied as follows:
### Single Responsibility Principle (SRP)
Example:
```go
type UserService struct {
userRepository UserRepository
}
func (us *UserService) CreateUser(user *User) error {
return us.userRepository.Create(user)
}
func (us *UserService) GetUserByID(id int) (*User, error) {</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We need LEGOs for Code</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/we-need-legos-for-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/we-need-legos-for-code/</guid>
      <description>## Playing with Legos
Legos are fun, they are composable. Code is not composable, not at least in the way we learn to code.
Different environments come with different constraints which end up with different code. Different ecosystems have different standards and ways to solve a problem.
Legos have been designed to have an incredibly rigid specification that has been upheld for many years. It is trivial to determine impostor bricks (I am looking at you Mega Blocks) from an actual Lego.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What holds us back</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/what-holds-us-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/what-holds-us-back/</guid>
      <description>I don’t know if I personally would say that my life has been “hard”. I hear people use this to describe their life; “I have fallen on hard times”. But I don’t know, it doesn’t seem to be a relatable feeling. I have had to solve “hard” problems. Whether it is a math problem with seemingly random symbols or trying to comprehend why my parents won’t get along with each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why soundbite should exist</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/blog/why-soundbite-should-exist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/blog/why-soundbite-should-exist/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR soundbite is a podcasting platform, supercharged by advancements in content discovery, to connect with your friends and your community before international influencers.
Authenticity is a commodity in modern day communication. When we wake up, we look at our phone, during breakfast, we look at our phone, at work when we are bored, we look at our phone, going to the bathroom? phone. Watching TV? phone. Avoiding going to bed? phone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>resume</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>I am a security engineer with a passion for building tools that make security easier for developers. My passion is making concepts accessible for everyone.
download | chris@breadchris.com
LunaSec: (YC S19) CTO 2020 - Current Open-source security tooling for developers and security teams
Critical vulnerability coverage Log4Shell, Spring4Shell, Protestware) for global security teams
LunaTrace: &amp;ldquo;inbox-zero&amp;rdquo; for supply chain security
LunaDefend: Zero trust input form protecting against OWASP top 10 vulnerabilities</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>talks</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/talks/</guid>
      <description>### 101 Ways Dependencies Can Ruin Your Day
slides
Dependencies are really messy and can cause a lot of problems. There are systemic problems that hackers can take advantage of.
### How do you design LEGOs for code?
slides
I have played with LEGOs all my life and I have been writing code for a while now. I have been thinking about how to make code feel more like LEGOs.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workflow Engine syntax isn&#39;t making me happy, halp</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/workflow-engine-syntax-isnt-making-me-happy-halp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/workflow-engine-syntax-isnt-making-me-happy-halp/</guid>
      <description>I have been building a workflow engine that can route strongly-typed data through durable functions (guaranteed to execute). These functions do not need to exist in the process, they could be remote APIs, grpc servers, a p2p connection with your friend&amp;rsquo;s computer. It supports streaming of data with observables, thanks to rxgo, meaning you can create rules to map, filter, reduce data without redeployment.
This is the sketch I have in my head, and have been trying to implement it here.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecting your body and your mind</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/connecting-your-body-and-your-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/connecting-your-body-and-your-mind/</guid>
      <description>If someone were to talk to me about connecting my body to my mind a decade ago, I would have thought they were full of it. Regularly practicing meditation and now yoga has really made me realize how stupid you must be not to build this connection with yourself. Humans all have this incredible biological computer sitting inside their head and if you treat it as just that, a computer, it can do cool things.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>let&#39;s see if this works</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/lets-see-if-this-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/lets-see-if-this-works/</guid>
      <description>So if my calculations are right, I should be able to do the following:
Save this post with the tag #100daystooffload
Click publish above
Reload the site at /@breadchris
I should be able to see this post
This flow is a solid step in the direction of where I want to take this tool. With a little bit of tweaking, I now have a way to publish my ideas to the Internet the way that I want to.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is a good refactoring task?</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/what-is-a-good-refactoring-task/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/what-is-a-good-refactoring-task/</guid>
      <description>There has been a part of this code that I have been wanting to refactor for a while. Patch on patch of this form has left this code in disarray. This code is actually quite important to this site as well. It is a general application form that leverages the power of Protobuf&amp;rsquo;s expressive type system to generate a form a user can interact with. I have some ideas for where I want to take this code, but they haven&amp;rsquo;t been a priority.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Today wasn&#39;t a 100% day</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/today-wasnt-a-100-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/today-wasnt-a-100-day/</guid>
      <description>Idk what happened this morning but I went through my normal routine and then something just hit me which crippled my momentum. I have learned that listening to my body and trying to meet it where it is at in the moment vs trying to fight the feeling pays dividends over time. I try to map the feeling to a probability of what it is that I need. Often this feeling comes from not having enough water, so I drank some water and took a 20 minute nap.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why aren&#39;t there more personal sites?</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/why-arent-there-more-personal-sites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/why-arent-there-more-personal-sites/</guid>
      <description>It bothers me that more people don&amp;rsquo;t have personal sites. In my opinion, we all do interesting things. In order to communicate the interesting things that we do, we need to provide others with an immersive experience of our world. Personal sites of designers and artists attempt to capture our imagination with an elegantly simple and refreshing display of their portfolios or wild 3d graphics. It makes sense why this isn&amp;rsquo;t the norm, these sites take time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Culture</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/hacking-culture/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/hacking-culture/</guid>
      <description>I had a call with a friend who was a hacker in the golden days of hacking. There were lots of exciting things happening in security as problems were unearthed, and solutions theorized. Over time, these problems that came up became solved. Buffers got compiler and runtime checks. SQL injection doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist when you use prepared statements. XSS doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist if you use React. The bread and butter of what hackers were poking at slowly shrunk as companies changed their development practices.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>just a test</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/just-a-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/just-a-test/</guid>
      <description>This is the post for today, lets see if i broke something.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what i have learned about the problem i want to solve</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/what-i-have-learned-about-the-problem-i-want-to-solve/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/what-i-have-learned-about-the-problem-i-want-to-solve/</guid>
      <description>There are many things that I could be doing. I have spent a lot of time doing cyber security, I have spent a lot of time coding, maybe if I am lucky I could be a baker from all the time I have spent baking. But there is only so much time in the day. There are only so many things that you can get 10,000 hours of mastery over. And even if you have &amp;ldquo;mastered&amp;rdquo; it, have you felt good doing it?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dogfooding</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/dogfooding/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/dogfooding/</guid>
      <description>I think there are some really cool things that you get when you dogfood the thing you are building. For those who are unfamiliar with &amp;ldquo;dogfood&amp;rdquo;, as it relates to the tech world, it means to use it yourself. I have not had much focus on the projects that I have been working on, and now that I am directly dogfooding the app, which aims to help me increase the frequency and quality of how I write, I am held accountable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>v0: a start</title>
      <link>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/v0-a-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://breadchris.com/thinkies/v0-a-start/</guid>
      <description>This post was written by a tool that I have been building for a while, and I think this is the first feature that is remotely helpful. I am writing this post in the browser and it is then going to get saved to the database. When I click the Publish button at the top of this page, then the post will be written to a file in LogSeq where I will push it to Github and link people to it from there.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
